Zweig, Friderike; Papers ger103
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Friderike Zweig Papers
1939-1970
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Zweig, Friderike Maria Burger Winternitz, 1882-1971
ger103
0.4 cubic ft.
This collection contains reproductions of correspondence of the novelist, translator, and biographer Friderike Maria Zweig.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives 1980
Biographical History
Born in Vienna, Friderike Maria Zweig (1882-1971) was a literary critic, novelist, translator, and biographer. She was married to the Viennese writer Stefan Zweig from 1920-1938 and later founded the Stefan Zweig Society, devoted to the study of his books.
Zweig died in Stamford, Connecticut and was survived by two daughters from her first marriage to Dr. Felix Elder von Winternitz.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists primarily of reproductions of correspondence, although there also is a small amount of subject material. Not all dates are inclusive.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has no series. It is arranged alphabetically.
World War, 1939-1945--Refugees; Women authors; Correspondence; Zweig, Friderike Maria Burger Winternitz, 1882-1971; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955; Fulop-Miller, Rene, 1891-1963
- Auernheimer, R. and Irene, Beale, 1942-1943; 1948 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 1)
- Broch, Herman, 1943; 1947 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 2)
- Dbln, Alfred, 1944-1945; 1970 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 3)
- Ehrenstein, Albert, 1942; 1947; 1950; Undated (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 4)
- Einstein, Albert, 1944 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 5)
- Fllop-Miller, Rene, 1941-1950; 1952-1964; Undated; nam_ger103-6 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 6)
- Jacob, H. E., 1943; 1947; 1951-1953 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 7)
- Kolb, Annette, 1946; Undated (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 8)
- Ludwig, Emil, 1942-1943; Undated (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 9)
- Maas, Joachim, 1947 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 10)
- Morgenstern, 1941-1942 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 11)
- Pauli, Hertha, 1943-1970; Undated (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 12)
- Polgar, Alfred, 1942 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 13)
- Schaeffer, Albrecht, 1945-1946 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 14)
- Silhergleit, Arthur, 1939 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 15)
- Ullman, Ludwig, 1943; 1945-1946; 1953; 1955-1957 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 16)
- Unruh, Fritz von, 1946; 1950-1952; 1962; Undated (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 17)
- Urzidil, Johannes (1 of 3), 1944-1957; 1959-1966; 1970; Undated (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 18)
- Urzidil, Johannes (2 of 3), 1944-1957; 1959-1966; 1970; Undated (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 19)
- Urzidil, Johannes (3 of 3), 1944-1957; 1959-1966; 1970; Undated (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 20)
- Victor, Walther, 1942; 1946-1948 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 21)
- Waldinger, Ernst, 1946; 1953; 1957; 1961; 1967 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 22)
- Werfel, Alma, 1940; 1942-1943; 1945-1946; 1950 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 23)
- Werfel, 1950; 1939/1970 (Box 1 (Friderike Zweig Papers ), Folder 24)